KEVIN ADRIAN RODRIGUEZ RUIZ

Software developer, Chemical engineer

About me

BSc. in Chemical engineer and MEng. in computing with more than five years of experience in software development.

Self-disciplined person and excited about integrating multiple disciplines and making things easier and accessible.

Interests

Computing, Bioinformatics. Modelling and Optimization. Learning new engineering/science topics.

Languages

Spanish (native) English (fluent) French (basic)

Contact

Bogotá, Colombia. 111156 (+57 1) 6698229 (+57) 3057052399



karodriguezr@unal.edu.co



<u>LinkedIn profile</u>



GitHub public repositories

SKILLS

Java, Javascript, Node.js, Python, Reactjs, Amazon Web Services, Spring Framework, Django, Git, Postgres, web applications, NoSQL databases, Scrum, Docker.

Programs: VS Code, Intellij Idea, Aspen Plus.

EMPLOYMENT

GNB Sudameris Bank (2020)

+ Java developer. Develop of financial web services consumed by the mobile applications. Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Amazon Web Services.

Amaris Consulting (2019 - 2020)

+ Full-stack developer. Develop of web services and use interfaces for the management of insurance policies. Technologies: Nodejs, TypeScript, Reactjs, Redux, Serverless Framework, Amazon Web Services.

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana (2018 - 2019)

+ Software developer. Design and development of Astrocyte Neuron Simulation Environment Platform (ANSEP). Web platform for the analysis of genome-scale metabolic models related to the study of neurodegenerative diseases. Technologies: Python, R, Django, Reactjs, Docker, Postgresgl.

Software Colombia SAS (2015 – 2018)

- + Full-Stack developer. Design, development a web platform for massive email marketing platform. Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs, Gradle, Amazon Web Services.
- + Software developer. Design, development and support of desktop applications signing information digitally, encrypting data and storing files in the cloud. Technologies: Javascript, Java and JavaFX.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2019	M. Eng. in Systems Engineering and Computing Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)
2018 – 2019	Exchange Student in the MSc in Advanced Catalysis and Molecular Modelling Universitat de Girona (Spain)
2009 – 2015	Bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)

SHORT COURSES

- Advanced Separation Operations. Separation Technologies in
 Biorefineries
 International Chair of Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Colombia
- 2017 Introduction to innovation and the use of technology for learning International School, Universidad Nacional de Colombia
- 2014 **Software maintenance, evolution, and re-engineering**International Chair of Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Colombia

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- + Rescurves. Open source MS Excel Add-in aimed to ease the three-dimensional plotting of residue curves maps for quaternary systems. Technologies: C#, VSTO.
- + Master's final work: CAMD. Desktop application to solve the Computer Aided Molecular Design (CAMD) problem of finding the most suitable solvent for a liquid-liquid separation. It makes use of multi-objective optimization and databases mining algorithms. Technologies: Java, Mongodb.